Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. John J. Hamilton papers, 1976-1982 RL.11329
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. John J. Hamilton papers
1976-1982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11329
1.5 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. John J. Hamilton was an executive with the agency during the 1970s and 1980s. Collection iIncludes company policy documents and reports, research reports, new business and client presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include JWT offices in San Francisco, India and Hong Kong; CBS; Deutsch Bank and Lufthansa. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. John J. Hamilton papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company Archives collections held in the Hartman Center:
JWT Frankfurt Office papers of Wilfried Henkel, Herbert Brungs, George Black; JWT San Francisco Office records.
Collection Overview
Includes company policy documents and reports, research reports, new business and client presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include JWT offices in San Francisco, India and Hong Kong; CBS; Deutsch Bank and Lufthansa. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- Costs; Advertising agencies; Advertising executives; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Deutsche Bank; Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.
- Collection Inventory, 1976-1982; 1
  - Account gains and losses, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1980 (Box 1)
  - CBS presentation, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Client retention program, 1980; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Consumer Reaction to Jewel Generic Products Wave II, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Food sales trends, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Gerd Elias, Deutsch Bank, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Hindustan Thompson Associates, Tea project, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Hispania, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Home Video Information and Entertainment (HVIE), 1981; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - JWT Group: A Company of Companies, 1980 (Box 2)
  - JWT San Francisco: One Approach to New Business, 1981 (Box 2)
  - JWT share of 1980 ad expenditures in 6 media, 1981 (Box 3)
  - JWT staffing system, 1982 (Box 2)
  - JWT USA print seminar, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Lufthansa information for JWT Hong Kong, 1976-1980 (Box 3)
  - Managers' Monthly Assessments, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Managers' Monthly Assessments, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Memoranda, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - New business status reports, 1981-1982; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - President's Forum, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Professional Development Handbook questionnaire, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Survey of creative workload by agency, 1981 (Box 3)
  - T-Plan (How it is used in U.S. offices, request from JWT London), 1981 (Box 3)
  - T-Plan Jeremy Bullmore questionnaire, approximately 1981 (Box 3)
  - Video Central/Creative Library, 1980 (Box 3)